Guide to the Time Inc. Video Group Records 1934-1989 MS 3009-RG 41
New-York Historical Society
- Series VII.B. Time-Life Films: Video Division Records, 1974-1983; 7 Linear feet 10 in records cartons
  - Subseries VII.B.1 Vice President of Programming and Production Richard Schilling Files, 1974-1982; 5.95 Linear feet in 8 records cartons
    The Vice President of Programming and Production Richard Schilling Files cover the period of 1974 to 1982. While some of the materials in this series were creating when Schilling was the vice president of multimedia, the majority of materials are from his time as vice president of programming and production. Included in this series are correspondence and subject files.
    The Vice President of Programming and Production Richard Schilling Files are arranged into two subsubseries:
    Subsubseries VII.B.1.a. Chronological Files
    Subsubseries VII.B.1.b. Subject Files
    - Subsubseries VII.B.1.a. Chronological Files, 1975-1980; 2.19 Linear feet in 4 records cartons
      The Chronological Files cover the period of 1975 to 1980 and focus on the finances and legal concerns of the Video Division. A chronological file, sometimes called a chron file, is kept to document daily activities of an office and are kept in chronological order. While majority of the materials were created while Schilling was part of the video division, there are some documents from when he was vice president of multimedia for Time-Life Films. Correspondence included in this subsubseries discuss revenue, orders, invoices, negotiations, agreements, sales, clearances, reputation, promotion for new series and books, staffing, meetings, insurance policies, possible projects, licensing, income, rights extensions, shipments, back log of contractual work, distribution, department reviews, and revenue.
      Arranged chronologically.
      - Chronological Files, 1975-1977 (Offsite-box 3371, Folder 21-28)
      - Chronological Files, 1977-1979 (Offsite-box 3373, Folder 1-17)
      - Chronological Files, 1979-1980 (Offsite-box 3374, Folder 1-9)
      - Chronological Files [RESTRICTED], 1975-1980 (Offsite-box R57)
    - Subsubseries VII.B.1.b. Subject Files, 1973-1982; 4.26 Linear feet in 7 records cartons
      The Subject Files cover the period of 1973 to 1982 and focus on the financing and promotion as well as possible future projects and legal issues. Included are clippings, proposals to the corporation for public broadcasting, press releases, programs, evaluation process agendas and Q and As, course reports, agreements, scripts, lists of titles from the production company EMI, lists of EMI units ordered, weekly Television Digest issues, newsletters, press kits, program outlines, book outlines, promotional booklets, financial analysis, invoices, lists of users, promotional mailers, booking schedules, copies of catalog records, lists of consultants, project reports, notes on reactions, blank questionnaires for consultants, Shakespeare in the classroom report, Shakespeare task force reports, lists of possible future projects, viewers guides to Shakespeare, Shakespeare on film newsletters, press kits, music cue sheet, lists of possible contributors, lists of co-productions sales and finances, sales forecasts, program evaluation cards, list of award winners, reports on BBC kids programming, sound effect library catalogs, and correspondence. Correspondence discusses reviews, television in college courses, sales, agreements, English as a second language, pricing policies, finances, critiques, effective writing techniques for executives, training, litigation, copyright, underwriters, university courses, clearance, agreements, distribution, screenings, rights, print library, marketing, promotion plan, March of Time, meeting summaries, contracts, masters of co-productions, recording/retention policies, multimedia expectations, preliminary work, project pitches, and status updates.
      - All the World's a Stage, 1978-1980 (Offsite-box 3374, Folder 10)
      - American Labor History [EMPTY], undated (Offsite-box 3374, Folder 11)
      - Anno Domini: South Korea [EMPTY], undated (Offsite-box 3374, Folder 12)
      - BBC, 1973-1980 (Offsite-box 3374, Folder 13-16)
      - BBC [RESTRICTED], 1973 (Offsite-box R57)
      - BBC, 1976-1981 (Offsite-box 3375, Folder 1-2)
      - BBC: Clearances, 1971-1982 (Offsite-box 3375, Folder 3-5)
      - BBC: Editing Issue, 1977-1979 (Offsite-box 3375, Folder 6)
      - BBC: Further Education, 1975-1980 (Offsite-box 3375, Folder 7)
      - BBC: Kelly's File, 1974-1976 (Offsite-box 3375, Folder 8)
      - BBC Publications, 1978-1981 (Offsite-box 3375, Folder 9)
      - BBC Radio, 1978 (Offsite-box 3375, Folder 10)
      - BBC Records, 1978 (Offsite-box 3375, Folder 11)
      - BBC: USA, 1975-1977 (Offsite-box 3375, Folder 12)
      - Co-Productions, 1976-1982, undated (Offsite-box 3375, Folder 13)
      - Co-Productions: Possibilities, 1977-1979 (Offsite-box 3375, Folder 14)
      - E: Miscellaneous [EMPTY], undated (Offsite-box 3375, Folder 15)
      - The Economic Society, 1976-1977 (Offsite-box 3375, Folder 16)
      - Educational Development Center: Harvard, 1976-1977 (Offsite-box 3375, Folder 17)
      - Eductronics, 1973-1974 (Offsite-box 3375, Folder 18)
      - EduTech, 1977-1978 (Offsite-box 3375, Folder 19)
      - Effective Writing for Executives, 1978-1982 (Offsite-box 3375, Folder 20-21)
      - Effective Writing for Executives [RESTRICTED], 1980 (Offsite-box R58)
      - Ellington, Duke, 1982 (Offsite-box 3375, Folder 22)
      - EMI Videograms Inc., 1979-1980 (Offsite-box 3375, Folder 23)
      - EMI Videograms Inc. [RESTRICTED], 1979 (Offsite-box R58)
      - Erie County BOCES: Copyright, 1977-1982 (Offsite-box 3375, Folder 24-27)
      - Erie County BOCES: Copyright [RESTRICTED], 1977-1980 (Offsite-box R58)
      - F: Miscellaneous [EMPTY], undated (Offsite-box 3375, Folder 28)
      - FilmsPlus, 1978, undated (Offsite-box 3376, Folder 1-2)
      - Food, Wine and Friends [RESTRICTED], 1981-1982 (Offsite-box R58)
      - Fox, 1980 (Offsite-box 3376, Folder 3)
      - Fox, Harry: Agency, 1980 (Offsite-box 3376, Folder 4)
      - Franklin Media [RESTRICTED], 1979-1980 (Offsite-box R58)
      - Gateway Productions, 1975-1977 (Offsite-box 3376, Folder 5)
      - Gateway Productions [RESTRICTED], 1977 (Offsite-box R58)
      - Gathering Storm, 1978 (Offsite-box 3376, Folder 6)
      - Glass Menagerie [RESTRICTED], 1980 (Offsite-box R58)
      - Go Play in a Nuclear Power Park, 1977 (Offsite-box 3376, Folder 7)
      - Good Guys Wear Black, 1979 (Offsite-box 3376, Folder 8)
      - Great Moments in Sports, 1975 (Offsite-box 3376, Folder 9)
      - Great Wallendas, undated (Offsite-box 3376, Folder 10)
      - Halloween [RESTRICTED], 1980-1981 (Offsite-box R58)
      - Hancock, John, 1979-1980 (Offsite-box 3376, Folder 11)
      - Hancock, John [RESTRICTED], 1979-1980 (Offsite-box R58)
      - Harper Valley PTA [RESTRICTED], 1980-1981 (Offsite-box R58)
      - HBO, 1975-1981 (Offsite-box 3376, Folder 12-14)
      - HBO [RESTRICTED], 1980 (Offsite-box R58)
      - HBO Sports, 1979 (Offsite-box 3376, Folder 15)
      - I: Miscellaneous, 1981 (Offsite-box 3376, Folder 16)
      - J: Miscellaneous [EMPTY], undated (Offsite-box 3376, Folder 17)
      - Jazz on a Summer's Day, 1979-1981 (Offsite-box 3376, Folder 18)
      - Jazz on a Summer's Day [RESTRICTED], 1982 (Offsite-box R58)
      - Jazz Projects, 1979-1980 (Offsite-box 3376, Folder 19)
      - Jones, Grace [RESTRICTED], 1979-1980 (Offsite-box R58)
      - K: Miscellaneous [EMPTY], undated (Offsite-box 3376, Folder 20)
      - Keys, Gary: Productions [RESTRICTED], 1979-1980 (Offsite-box R58)
      - Kid From Left Field, 1980 (Offsite-box 3376, Folder 21)
      - King Features, 1981-1982 (Offsite-box 3376, Folder 22)
      - Kinks, 1979-1982 (Offsite-box 3376, Folder 23)
      - Kinks [RESTRICTED], 1979-1981 (Offsite-box R58)
      - Kino International Corporation, 1980-1982 (Offsite-box 3376, Folder 24)
      - Korty Films, 1979-1981 (Offsite-box 3376, Folder 25)
      - Korty Films [RESTRICTED], 1979 (Offsite-box R58)
      - L: Miscellaneous [EMPTY], undated (Offsite-box 3376, Folder 26)
      - Leakey, Richard: In Search of Man, 1979-1981 (Offsite-box 3376, Folder 27)
      - Licensed Movies [RESTRICTED], 1979-1980 (Offsite-box R58)
      - Life Goes to the Movies, 1974-1977 (Offsite-box 3376, Folder 28)
      - Life Goes to the Movies [RESTRICTED], 1978 (Offsite-box R58)
      - Life Goes to War, 1977-1978 (Offsite-box 3376, Folder 29)
      - Life on Earth, 1977-1981 (Offsite-box 3376, Folder 30)
      - Lincoln Show, 1980 (Offsite-box 3376, Folder 31)
      - Listening, 1982 (Offsite-box 3376, Folder 32)
      - Lloyd, Harold: Films, 1976-1981 (Offsite-box 3376, Folder 33-34)
      - Lloyd, Harold: Films [RESTRICTED], 1976-1978 (Offsite-box R58)
      - Long Search, 1975-1980 (Offsite-box 3376, Folder 35-37)
      - Long Search, undated (Offsite-box 3377, Folder 1)
      - Management Skills for Supervisors, 1981-1982 (Offsite-box 3377, Folder 2-4)
      - March of Time Correspondence, 1975-1980 (Offsite-box 3377, Folder 5)
      - Marlin Motion Pictures, 1981 (Offsite-box 3377, Folder 6)
      - Masters and Johnson, 1980 (Offsite-box 3377, Folder 7)
      - Masters and Johnson [RESTRICTED], 1980 (Offsite-box R58)
      - Matsushita Electronic Corporation of America [RESTRICTED], 1974 (Offsite-box R58)
      - Mattel Electronics, 1980 (Offsite-box 3377, Folder 8)
      - MCA, 1980 (Offsite-box 3377, Folder 9)
      - McGraw Hill Films, 1977 (Offsite-box 3377, Folder 10)
      - McHale Productions, 1976-1977 (Offsite-box 3377, Folder 11)
      - McHale Productions [RESTRICTED], 1977 (Offsite-box R58)
      - Meatballs, 1979-1980 (Offsite-box 3377, Folder 12)
      - Media Basics, 1982-1983 (Offsite-box 3377, Folder 13)
      - Media Home Entertainment, 1980-1981 (Offsite-box 3377, Folder 14)
      - Media Home Entertainment [RESTRICTED], 1981 (Offsite-box R58)
      - Media Probes, 1977-1982 (Offsite-box 3377, Folder 15-16)
      - Media Probes [RESTRICTED], 1981-1982 (Offsite-box R58)
      - Meisel, Tony, 1980 (Offsite-box 3377, Folder 17)
      - Mendelson, Lee, 1980 (Offsite-box 3377, Folder 18)
      - Merrill Lynch, 1978 (Offsite-box 3377, Folder 19)
      - Metropolitan Museum of Art: Producer, 1975-1977 (Offsite-box 3377, Folder 20)
      - Metropolitan Museum of Art: Producer [RESTRICTED], 1977 (Offsite-box R58)
      - Microbes and Men, 1976 (Offsite-box 3377, Folder 21)
      - Midwest Film Productions [RESTRICTED], 1980 (Offsite-box R58)
      - Proposals, 1979-1980 (Offsite-box 3377, Folder 22-23)
      - Rust Never Sleeps [RESTRICTED], 1979-1981 (Offsite-box R58)
      - Search for Alexander, 1981 (Offsite-box 3377, Folder 24)
      - Shakespeare, 1975-1978 (Offsite-box 3377, Folder 25-27)
      - Shakespeare, 1975-1979 (Offsite-box 3378, Folder 1-6)
      - Shakespeare [RESTRICTED], 1978 (Offsite-box R58)
      - Shock of the New, 1980 (Offsite-box 3378, Folder 7)
  - Subseries VII.B.2. Time-Life Video Club Files, 1979-1983; 1.05 Linear feet in 3 records cartons
    The Time-Life Home Video Service was first proposed in 1978 as subscription service that would distribute and sell pre-recorded and blank video cassettes to private consumers. The service was officially launched in 1979 as the Time-Life Video Club. At the time the service officially launched, the Video Division decided to follow the model used by the Book-of-the-Month Club, another subsidiary of Time Inc., and only distribute pre-recorded content. The content offered included feature films, dramas, comedies, children's' shows, sports, and how-to's. Much of the advertising and launch campaign for this service was handled by the Book-of-the-Month Club.
    After the service's launch, the Time-Life Video Club was faced with a variety of problems. One of the main issues was that the service could not secure the rights to enough lucrative films. Without these titles, the Time-Life Video Club was not able to promote the service in the way that they had originally planned leading to unfavorable sales. Due to these issues, Time Inc. sold the Video Club to Vestron Inc. in 1981.
    Time-Life Films: Time-Life Video Club: 1978-1981. Time Inc. Subject Files (MS 3009-RG 1), New-York Historical Society
    The Time-Life Video Club Files cover the period of 1979 to 1983 and focus on the service's finances as well as its sale to Vestron. Included in this subseries are financial proposals, agreement outlines, market evaluations, notes on finances, consumer video report, Time-Life Video Club catalogs, weekly sales reports, financial reports, design proposals, sales and enrollment analysis, contracts and agreements, program lists, rights summary reports, marketing plans, multimedia catalogs, invoices, and correspondence. The correspondence discuss proposed deals, finances, consumer videos, bulletin changes, design proposals, contracts and agreements, requests for information about rights, revenue, and sales.
    - Agreements and Contracts, 1980 (Offsite-box 3378, Folder 8)
    - Agreements and Contracts [RESTRICTED], 1980 (Offsite-box R58)
    - Assumptions, 1981 (Offsite-box 3378, Folder 9)
    - AVCO Embassy Pictures Co., 1979 (Offsite-box 3378, Folder 10)
    - Billing and Finances, 1980 (Offsite-box 3378, Folder 11)
    - Book of the Month Club, 1981 (Offsite-box 3378, Folder 12)
    - Cinema 5 Consumer Video, 1981 (Offsite-box 3378, Folder 13)
    - Club Sales Progress Reports, 1980 (Offsite-box 3378, Folder 14)
    - Club Shutdown Analysis, 1981 (Offsite-box 3378, Folder 15)
    - Club Shutdown Analysis [RESTRICTED], 1981 (Offsite-box R58)
    - Financial Analysis, 1979-1983 (Offsite-box 3378, Folder 16-17)
    - International Video Valuation, 1980 (Offsite-box 3378, Folder 18)
    - International Video Valuation [RESTRICTED], 1980 (Offsite-box R58)
    - Invoices, undated (Offsite-box 3378, Folder 19)
    - Kinks: P&L: Retail, 1980 (Offsite-box 3378, Folder 20)
    - Kinks: Sales Report: Retail, 1981 (Offsite-box 3378, Folder 21)
    - New Chart of Accounts, 1981 (Offsite-box 3378, Folder 22)
    - Notes, undated (Offsite-box 3378, Folder 23)
    - Participation/Royalty Reports, 1981-1982 (Offsite-box 3378, Folder 24)
    - Profit and Sales Analysis, undated (Offsite-box 3378, Folder 25)
    - Program Lists, 1979 (Offsite-box 3372, Folder 1)
    - Retail Ledger Entries, 1980-1981 (Offsite-box 3372, Folder 2)
    - Rough Print Outs: February 4 and 5, 1981 (Offsite-box 3372, Folder 3)
    - Sales and Promotional Cassettes, 1980 (Offsite-box 3372, Folder 4)
    - Set of Print Outs, 1981 (Offsite-box 3372, Folder 5)
    - Theatrical Scenarios: February 9 and 10, 1981 (Offsite-box 3372, Folder 6)
    - Theatrical Model: 5 Year Plan, 1980 (Offsite-box 3372, Folder 7)
    - Time-Life Films: Staff Cassette Purchases, undated (Offsite-box 3372, Folder 8)
    - Time-Life Video: Club Bulletins, 1979-1981 (Offsite-box 3372, Folder 9)
    - Time-Life Video: Consumer Video Financial Report, 1980 (Offsite-box 3372, Folder 10)
    - Time-Life Video: Consumer Video Report, undated (Offsite-box 3372, Folder 11)
    - Time-Life Video: Retail/International, undated (Offsite-box 3372, Folder 12)
    - Vestron Agreement, 1981 (Offsite-box 3372, Folder 13)
    - Video Club Rights Inventory, 1980-1981 (Offsite-box 3372, Folder 14)
- Series VII.C. Time-Life Films: Multimedia Division Records, 1966-1977; 4.4 Linear feet in 4 records cartons and 2 flat boxes
  The Multimedia Division of Time-Life Films is first mentioned in department head lists in 1978. The following year, the division is no longer listed and appears to have been absorbed by the Video Enterprise Division. While department head lists offer little information, the materials within this series imply that the division existed before 1978. The main purpose of this division was to create educational kits that could be used in classrooms.
  Personnel and Organization: Department Head Lists. Time Inc. Reference Files (MS 3009-RG 3), The New-York Historical Society.
  The Time-Life Films: Multimedia Division Records cover the period of 1966 to 1977 with the bulk covering the period of 1974 to 1975. The focus of this series is on the production of educational kits that Time-Life films distributed and sold to schools and universities. Included in this subseries are clippings, bibliographies, teaching guides, drafts of guides, notes, episode overviews, sound scripts, overdue transparencies forms, cue sheets, film lists, shooting masters, filmstrip reports, frame lists, scripts, personnel lists, photograph order forms, invoices, project overviews, story boards, catalog listings, program guides, agreements, and correspondence. The Correspondence discuss comments on scripts, production of films, filmstrips, transparencies, payments, photographs, scripts, language levels, content issues, agreements, and reproduction. Additionally, there are two multimedia kits that are examples of the materials that were distributed and sold to schools and universities.
  - Emergence of Man, 1974-1975 (Offsite-box 3372, Folder 15-16)
  - Emergence of Man: Budget, 1974-1975 (Offsite-box 3372, Folder 17-18)
  - Emergence of Man: Cro Magnon Man, 1974 (Offsite-box 3372, Folder 19)
  - Emergence of Man: Film, 1975 (Offsite-box 3372, Folder 20)
  - Emergence of Man: The First Americans, 1974 (Offsite-box 3372, Folder 21)
  - Emergence of Man: The First Cities, 1974 (Offsite-box 3372, Folder 22)
  - Emergence of Man: The First Farmers, 1974 (Offsite-box 3372, Folder 23)
  - Emergence of Man: The First Men, undated (Offsite-box 3372, Folder 24)
  - Emergence of Man: Life Before Man, 1974 (Offsite-box 3372, Folder 25)
  - Emergence of Man: Neanderthal, 1974 (Offsite-box 3372, Folder 26)
  - Emergence of Man: Pictures: Returned Letters, 1974-1975 (Offsite-box 3372, Folder 27)
  - Emergence of Man: Pictures: Sources, 1974 (Offsite-box 3372, Folder 28)
  - Emergence of Man: Teacher's Guides, 1974 (Offsite-box 3372, Folder 29)
  - Human Behavior: Filmstrip Scripts, 1975-1976 (Offsite-box 3372, Folder 30)
  - Human Behavior: Filmstrip Scripts [RESTRICTED], 1976 (Offsite-box R58)
  - Human Behavior: The Psychology of the Self, 1977 (Offsite-box 3379)
    Label on top of box: "Example of 1970's Time Life Multimedia Product: 6 audio tapes, 6 filmstrips and booklet (c. 1977) based on the Human Behavior: The Psychology of the Self Time Life Book series"
    Box contains:
    1 Human Behavior: The Psychology of the Self program guide
    a letter to customers from a member of the Time-Life Multimedia customer relations team
    an advertising card for a free audiovisual processing kit from Time-Life Multimedia
    6 audiocassettes
    6 canisters with 35mm filmstrips
  - Human Body: Copy of Catalog Listing, undated (Offsite-box 3381, Folder 1)
  - Human Body: Filmstrip Scripts, 1973-1976 (Offsite-box 3381, Folder 2)
  - Life Before Birth: Captioned, 1973-1975 (Offsite-box 3381, Folder 3)
  - Life Before Birth: Captioned [RESTRICTED], 1974 (Offsite-box R58)
  - Success: Filmstrip Series, 1975-1976, undated (Offsite-box 3381, Folder 4-5)
  - Success: Filmstrips Series [RESTRICTED], 1975 (Offsite-box R58)
  - Survival and the Senses: Brain and Nervous System, Undated (Offsite-box 3381, Folder 6)
  - Survival and the Senses: Budget, 1974 (Offsite-box 3381, Folder 7)
  - Survival and the Senses: Consultants, 1973-1974 (Offsite-box 3381, Folder 8)
  - Survival and the Senses: Film Lists, undated (Offsite-box 3381, Folder 9)
  - Survival and the Senses: Hearing, 1974 (Offsite-box 3381, Folder 10)
  - Survival and the Senses: Other Senses, 1974 (Offsite-box 3381, Folder 11)
  - Survival and the Senses: Sight, 1974 (Offsite-box 3381, Folder 12)
  - Survival and the Senses: Taste and Smell, 1974 (Offsite-box 3381, Folder 13)
  - Survival and the Senses: Teaching Guides, 1966-1973 (Offsite-box 3381, Folder 14)
  - Survival and the Senses: Touch, undated (Offsite-box 3381, Folder 15)
  - Time-Life Nature Series, 1974-1975 (Offsite-box 3381, Folder 16-17)
  - Time-Life Nature Series [RESTRICTED], undated (Offsite-box R58)
  - Time-Life Nature Series: The Birds, 1974-1975 (Offsite-box 3381, Folder 18)
  - Time-Life Nature Series: Budget, 1974-1975 (Offsite-box 3381, Folder 19-20)
  - Time-Life Nature Series: Consultant, 1974-1975 (Offsite-box 3381, Folder 21)
  - Time-Life Nature Series: Consultants [RESTRICTED], 1974 (Offsite-box R58)
  - Time-Life Nature Series: Creatures: Budget, 1974-1975 (Offsite-box 3381, Folder 22)
  - Time-Life Nature Series: Cut Sheets, 1975 (Offsite-box 3381, Folder 23)
  - Time-Life Nature Series: Fishes, undated (Offsite-box 3381, Folder 24)
  - Time-Life Nature Series: The Insects, 1974-1975 (Offsite-box 3381, Folder 25)
  - Time-Life Nature Series: Mammals, 1974-1975 (Offsite-box 3381, Folder 26)
  - Time-Life Nature Series: Man and the Other Animals, 1974-1975 (Offsite-box 3382, Folder 1)
  - Time-Life Nature Series: Teacher's Guides, 1975 (Offsite-box 3382, Folder 2)
  - World War II: Time Capsule: Classroom Research Unit, undated (Offsite-box 3380)
    Label inside box: "World War II: Time Capsule: Classroom Research Unit Time Capsules/1939, 1940, 1941, 1942, 1943, 1944, 1945 Original recordings from the The March of Time Radio: Side 1: Hitler's March on Czechoslovakia Side 2: The United States' First Week at War Filmstrips to Accompany the Recordings Time Chart of War Years Events War Maps - European and Pacific Theaters Documents: Charlottesville Address, Four Freedoms Speech, Atlantic Charter, Declaration of War Speech, Reports on Casablanca Teheran and Yalta Conferences Teacher's Guide including Historical Notes, 10 Lesson Plans, Further Reading and Quizzes"
    Contains:
    1 sealed phonograph record with a set of instructions on the record's use
    1 poster with a set of maps on one side and a timeline on the other side
    1 folder with supplemental teaching documents
    1 World War II: Time Capsule: Classroom Research Unit Teacher's Guide
    6 Time Capsule Books for 1940 through 1945.
    2 contains with 35mm filmstrips
- Series VII.D. Time-Life Films: Special Projects Division: Television Book Records, 1934-1979; 25.5 Linear feet in 27 records cartons
  In 1974, after the success of its television series Wild, Wild World of Animals, Time-Life Films created a series of books to accompany the show. With the launch of this new project, Time-Life Films created a special projects division which would handle projects that were outside its normal purview. While initially launched with just Wild, Wild World of Animals in mind, the television books department of the special projects division ended up creating books for a number of Time-Life Films shows. Since Time-Life Films was not set up to publish books, it worked with Time-Life Books on these projects. The television book staff were responsible to creating the actual content of the books while Time-Life Books staff were responsible for printing and publishing the books.
  Time-Life Films: T-L Television Books. Time Inc. Subject Files (MS 3009-RG 1), New-York Historical Society
  The Television Book Records cover the period of 1934 to 1979 with the bulk covering 1975 to 1975. The focus of the materials in this series is on the production of books to accompany television shows produced by Time-Life Films. Production includes research, editing, and page layouts.
  The Time-Life Films: Special Projects Division: Television Book Records are divided into six subseries:
  Subseries VII.D.1. Editor Charles Osborne: Correspondence Files
  Subseries VII.D.2. Book Production Files
  Subseries VII.D.3. Life Goes to War Copy Files
  Subseries VII.D.4. Wild, Wild World of Animals Copy Files
  Subseries VII.D.5. Wild, Wild World of Animals Research and Production Files
  Subseries VII.D.6. Melissa Wanamaker Carbon Files